Jamie Parkinson

I am a 4th year Theoretical Physics student at UCL, interested in applying the skills from my degree in real-world situations. My research in theoretical physics has lead me to want to apply novel mathematical techniques and physical intuition in practical programming problems.

Education

University College London (UCL) - Theoretical Physics MSci

[2012 -]

- 1st year average mark 86.6%
- 2nd year average mark 87.8%
- 3rd year average mark 81.0%
- Awarded the Oliver Lodge Prize for best performance in first year physics.
- Studies have been as mathematically and computationally focused as available options have allowed.
- Computational work has spanned quite a wide range: I have taken courses in Java and Mathematica (all with marks around 90%), have completed a project that largely consisted of Angular JS work, and have conducted summer research projects that used mostly C++ and Python - languages I'm very comfortable with. I'm familiar with R, MATLAB and F#, and have at various times worked with JavaScript, PHP, SQL, C#, IDL and more.
- I am extremely familiar with and proficient in the use of the bash shell, and well accustomed to the use of version control systems (git).

Bilborough College, Nottingham - A-Levels

[2010 - 2012]

- Maths, Further Maths, Physics A*
- AS Levels: History and Extended Project A

The Nottingham Bluecoat School - GCSEs

[2005-2010]

• 9 A*s, 4 As

Employment

UCL Physics Department: Project Student

[June 2015 - September 2015]

- Work during the summer with Prof. Ian Ford funded by the EPSRC Vacation Bursary.
- A paper from this, of which I am first author, is to appear soon in *Molecular Simulation*.
- This involved both mostly computational but also some pen-and-paper maths work.
- Computational work consisted of a suite of Python and bash scripts (and a little C++) for use on the Legion@UCL HPC facility, as well as some additions to existing FORTRAN code. As such I do have some HPC experience.
- Presented preliminary results at the University of Helsinki.

UCL Physics Department: Project Student

[June 2014 - March 2015]

• Work during the summer with Dr. Stephen Hogan funded by the EPSRC Vacation Bursary.

• Developed C++ software from scratch including the invention of a novel techique for caching of field values on a grid.

Salutaris Medical Devices, Ltd.: Associate

[Jan 2013 - Jan 2015]

- The company is developing a radiotherapy procedure for treating Wet AMD.
- Responsibilities including office-keeping, liaising with staff both in the company and at Imperial College London, quality control and health and safety.

University of Leicester Physics Department: Work Experience

[March 2009]

• Completed an undergraduate research project - the results were used as model data in the following year. Involved lab work and IDL programming.

British Home Stores: Sales Associate

[May 2012 - September 2012]

• Worked with customers and on tills, which required efficiency and teamwork.

Interests

• Music: Grade 8+ proficiency on double bass and piano. I play as principal and co-principal bass in several orchestras, and am actively involved with the UCL Chamber Music Club. I have also worked as a rehearsal pianist for theatre productions.

References

Available upon request.